Osip Bogdanov

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Details

Moscow, Russia live:.cid.ffa70d5eadb43221 progod128@gmail.com

Skills

JavaScript: ES6,ES7,ES8

TypeScript

Angular

React.js

Next.js

HTML5

CSS3/SASS/BootStrap

Node

PHP

Python

MySQL

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

ExpressJS

CI/CD

Docker

Languages

Russian/Serbian

English

Hobbies

Running, Swimming, Basketball

Profile

Specially Crypto Currency, React/React Native/Angular/Vue(MERN stack), ASP.NET! Looking for an experienced developer to take your Web/Mobile project off the ground? I might be the right person for you. I have the necessary skill set to develop a complex web App. My experience includes working on a number of applications for business, such as CRM, Lead Management, ERP, Devops.Hosting, and more. I have been programming since 2012. Throughout this time I have developed over 30 web Applications for both startups and established businesses from all over the world. I have developed a range of web solutions for clients from Western Europe and the USA. I have built customized websites to the highest specifications and carry out routine site maintenance. My biggest strengths are the ability to think out of the box, strong work ethic, and working well under pressure.

- * JavaScript stack:
- 1. ReactJS
- 2. VueJS
- 3. jQuery (Plugin Dev)
- 4. NodeJS
- * Databases:
- 1. Mysql
- 2. MongoDB
- 3. PostGreSql
- 4. NoSql
- 5. Firebase

Best Regards.

Employment History

Full-Stack Web Developer | Waveguide LLC

June 2011 - April 2012

- Built reusable, maintainable device fixing portal configurable to other business models
- Added report feature to show customers car fixing process.
- Taking leadership role on a project
- Fixing bugs on main website

Senior Full-Stack Web Developer | CyberCoders

August 2012 - February 2015

- Implemented back-end technologies like RDBMS, MySQL and JDBC.
- Designed CSS based page layouts that are cross-browser compatible and standards-compliant.
- Responsible for implementing and development of the web pages from mockups.
- Deep understanding and hands on experience in various stages of SDLC including direct client communication, requirement gathering and involvement in enterprise design.

Frontend Engineer | Shopee

May 2015 - February 2017

Develop performant and optimized web applications

- Build and upgrade internal tools and libraries to improve developer experience
- •Advocate new technologies and best practices within the team My key contributions are:
- •Built a rich set of development tools to improve developer experience (DX), such as chrome extension, cli tools, custom CI pipeline
- •Set up performance metrics monitoring platform
- •Upgraded React 16 and migrated legacy code
- •Optimized webpack bundle size to reduce load time

Technology used:

• React, Redux, Flow Type, webpack, Jest, puppeteer

Senior Full-Stack Web Developer | Ninja Van

May 2017 - January 2018

- Lead in implementing style guide on Angular powered frontend portal. Built a suite of reusable Angular directives and a set of Sass utility functions.
- Lead and developed a React powered consumer web application within 2 months from scratch.
- Frontend: React Native, React, React Router, Redux, Redux Saga, webpack, AngularJS, CSS, SCSS
- Backend: Java Play Framework, Lombok, Jackson, MySQL
- Tools: Git, Jira, Bamboo, BitBucket

Senior Full-Stack Web Engineer | VolKno

May 2018 - February 2019

- Working knowledge of front-end optimization and performance techniques
- Build, design and create robust prompt page interface from IBM Cognos framework into Angular 9 framework
- Serve as an active role in structuring single page applications to make easy to maintain

Senior Web Engineer | Yuzu Solutions LLC

June 2019 - January 2020

- Responsible for the development of new software products, from wireframe to successful deployment
- Utilize React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Netlify, FaunaDB, FQL, and PHP to implement scalable full-stack software solutions
- Interview candidates and evaluate technical assessments

Education

National Research Nuclear University

Bachelor of Computer Science (BCompSc), Computer science

Other Experiences

Responsive Design, Front-end Development, Single-page Applications (SPA), Cloud, ESLint, Koala